<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Michele Scandola&#39;s personal webpage</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Michele Scandola&#39;s personal webpage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A new article is out: The Motor Unawareness Assessment (MUNA): A new tool for the assessment of Anosognosia for hemiplegia</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-16-muna/muna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-16-muna/muna/</guid>
      <description>Dear all, it is with extreme plaseure that I am announcing the new article of Valentina Moro (that I am co-authoring).
 Moro, V., Besharati, S., Scandola, M., Bertagnoli, S., Gobbetto, V., Ponzo, S., Bulgarelli, C., Fotopoulou, A., &amp;amp; Jenkinson, P.M. (2021) The Motor Unawareness Assessment (MUNA): A new tool for the assessment of Anosognosia for hemiplegia, Journal of Clinical and Experimental Neuropsychology, https://doi.org/10.1080/13803395.2021.1876842
 Abstract: Introduction: Anosognosia for hemiplegia (AHP) is a condition in which patients with paralysis are unaware of their motor deficits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New registered report! Modulating preferences during intertemporal choices through exogenous midfrontal theta transcranial alternating current.</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-10-regrep-fusco/regrepfusco2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-10-regrep-fusco/regrepfusco2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am happy to announce that Gabriele Fusco&amp;rsquo;s Registered Report
&lt;em&gt;Modulating preferences during intertemporal choices
through exogenous midfrontal theta transcranial alternating current&lt;/em&gt;,
which I am co-authoring,
received a &amp;ldquo;In Principle Acceptance&amp;rdquo; by Cortex!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint! The development of a standard procedure for the optimal reliability-feasibility trade-off in Multilevel Linear Models analyses in Psychology and Neuroscience.</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-09-random-effects/standardrandomeffects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-09-random-effects/standardrandomeffects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new preprint was released yesterday February $8^{th}$!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new article is out: Anosognosia for theory of mind deficits: A single case study and a review of the literature</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-02-neuropsychologia-tom-awareness-deficit/a-new-article-is-out-anosognosia-for-theory-of-mind-deficits-a-single-case-study-and-a-review-of-the-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-02-neuropsychologia-tom-awareness-deficit/a-new-article-is-out-anosognosia-for-theory-of-mind-deficits-a-single-case-study-and-a-review-of-the-literature/</guid>
      <description>Dear all, it is with extreme plaseure that I am announcing the new article of Valentina Pacella (that I am co-authoring).
 Pacella, V., Scandola, M., Beccherle, M., Bulgarelli, C., Avesani, R., Carbognin, G., Agostini, G., Thiebaut de Schotten, M., &amp;amp; Moro, V. (2020). Anosognosia for theory of mind deficits: A single case study and a review of the literature. Neuropsychologia, 148. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2020.107641
 Abstract: Being aware of one&amp;rsquo;s own ability to interact socially is crucial to everyday life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The `bmscstan` package is on CRAN!</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-09-09-bmscstan-cran/the-bmscstan-package-is-on-cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-09-09-bmscstan-cran/the-bmscstan-package-is-on-cran/</guid>
      <description>Hi all!
After a long journey, the bmscstan package is finally on CRAN, with a comprehensive vignette that shows how to use the package and how to check if everything is OK.
The idea is to further extend its functions to non-gaussian dependent variables, however, this version is already ready to use.
You can find its validation here.
Dear all, I am very happy to announce that bmscstan, the R package for Bayesian Multilevel Single Case Models is on CRAN: https://t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint! Gesture errors in left and right hemisphere damaged patients</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-08-14-preprint-gestures/gesture_errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-08-14-preprint-gestures/gesture_errors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new preprint was released today August $12^{th}$!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New R package on github! bmscstan: Bayesian Multilevel Single Case models</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-08-06-bmscstan/new-r-package-on-github-bmscstan-bayesian-multilevel-single-case-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-08-06-bmscstan/new-r-package-on-github-bmscstan-bayesian-multilevel-single-case-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The version 1.0.0 of the package &lt;code&gt;bmscstan&lt;/code&gt; is ready to use!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its purpose is to provide a general, simple interface to analyse
single case studies with an lme4-like syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find it on my github page, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/michelescandola/bmscstan,&#34;&gt;https://github.com/michelescandola/bmscstan,&lt;/a&gt;
and you can install it by typing in the R console
&lt;code&gt;devtools::install_github(michelescandola/bmscstan)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint! Bayesian Multilevel Single Case Models using &#39;Stan&#39;</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-08-03-preprint-bmscstan/new-preprint-bayesian-multilevel-single-case-models-using-stan-a-new-tool-to-study-single-cases-in-neuropsychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-08-03-preprint-bmscstan/new-preprint-bayesian-multilevel-single-case-models-using-stan-a-new-tool-to-study-single-cases-in-neuropsychology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new preprint was released today!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint! Peripersonal space from a multisensory perspective</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-07-29-preprint-pps/new-preprint-peripersonal-space-from-a-multisensory-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-07-29-preprint-pps/new-preprint-peripersonal-space-from-a-multisensory-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new preprint was released today July $29^{th}$!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>